Hi, this is John Stewart and this is some repair tips for your tent.
The first thing you're going to run into when repairing a tent, is you normally get small holes, rips in your tent, the mesh and other parts of the tent.
The easiest way to repair these is Duct tape.
You can put a piece of Duct tape on the inside of the rip, and on the outside of the rip, and just sandwich it together.
This stuff will hold up during your camping trip, but you do want to get it further repaired once you get back.
Other things you might run into is a broken pole.
Poles will tend to crack once they get bent into funky shapes that you might put them into.
When you do encounter this, if the crack is small, once again, put some Duct tape over it and this will keep it from expanding and getting bigger.
If you break a pole in half, you can repair this be having an extra farel, or a pole protector.
Another way to do this, is to take two really hard sticks, duct tape them on there together.
This will get you through a camping trip, but you'll probably want to replace your pole after that.
If the pole's bungee breaks on the inside, the pole will still go together, it's just that you have to put it together piece by piece instead of just having it snap together.
If your rain fly begins to leak, or your tent begins to leak, you need to take and replace the seam sealing on it.
You just buy a tube of seam sealer, run it across the seams, and this will waterproof your seams to where you don't have any leaks or drains into your tent.
If you have punctures in your ground fly, you probably ought to replace the ground fly, because this is the main protector from the bottom of your tent, so you don't want to have any punctures or anything like that in your ground fly.
And this is how, some repair tips for setting up your tent.